xrite.com 2019-11-12

# Privacy Policy

### Updated November 1 2018

This Online Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains how X-Rite, Inc. and its X-Rite-branded affiliates (“X-Rite”) handle Personal Data provided to us on websites, mobile sites, mobile applications, and other digital services and products controlled by X-Rite that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, “X-Rite Sites”). X-Rite is the data controller for the processing of Personal Data under applicable law.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to X-Rite Sites that do not link to this Privacy Policy or to third-party websites to which the X-Rite Sites may link.

### Summary

This summary section provides a brief overview of our Privacy Policy. Please read the full Privacy Policy for more detailed information.

  * Information We Collect
  * How We Use Your Information
  * Information We Share
  * Your Privacy Choices
  * Security
  * Accessing Our Sites Globally
  * Changes to Our Privacy Policy

##  Information We Collect

X-Rite collects the following types of information through the X-Rite Sites:

  * Information you provide. Personal Data you provide when registering for our products and services, responding to questionnaires or surveys, or contacting X-Rite customer service.
  * Information collected automatically. Your IP address and non-identifying information about your use of X-Rite Sites may be collected automatically using tracking technologies, such as cookies. Your website browser software can be set to reject all cookies; however, cookies can allow you to take advantage of some of the site’s essential features, which may not work if you reject cookies.
  * Information collected from other sources. We may combine information about you from X-Rite Sites, information collected offline, or from external parties.

##  How We Use Your Information

X-Rite uses the information we collect for the following purposes:

  * To provide you with the X-Rite products and services you request.
  * To offer and provide information about similar and/or related products and services.
  * To customize and improve your experience on X-Rite Sites.
  * To generally improve our products and X-Rite Sites and other internal business purposes.
  * To notify and report to authorities under our legal obligations.

Under European data protection laws, X-Rite must have a legal basis to process your Personal Data. The legal basis that applies in a particular instance will depend on the specific purposes described above for which X-Rite is processing your Personal Data:

  * In certain instances, X-Rite may ask for your consent to collect and process your Personal Data. Should you choose to provide your consent, you may later withdraw your consent by contacting us as described in the “Your Privacy Choices” section. Please note that the withdrawal of consent will not affect processing which has already occurred. 
  * In other instances, the processing of your Personal Data may be necessary in order to comply with an applicable law or regulation or for the performance of a contract to which you are subject. You may not be able to opt out of this processing, or your choice to opt out may impact our ability to perform a contractual obligation otherwise owed to you.
  * In yet other instances, X-Rite may process your Personal Data based on X-Rite’s legitimate interests in communicating with you about our products and services, and about scientific research and educational opportunities. You have the right to opt out of all such processing of your Personal Data. You may do so by contacting us as described in the “Your Privacy Choices” section.

Processing operations may include the recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction of Personal Data. The Personal Data we collect about you may be stored for ten years following the most recent interaction we have had with you, after which point it will be archived only for so long as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out above, in accordance with applicable laws.

##  Information We Share

X-Rite does not sell or disclose your Personal Data to third parties without your consent, except:

  * To affiliates and third-party service providers to provide services and information on our sites, including online marketing and advertising, and to support our business operations. We require these parties to handle Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * To affiliates to offer and provide information about related products and services. We do not share Personal Data from countries that require consent, unless consent has been obtained in advance of sharing with affiliates. We require these parties to handle your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * To our distribution channel partners in connection with the sale and distribution of our products and services. We require these parties to handle your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * To another company in connection with the sale or transfer of one of our product lines or divisions, which includes the services provided through one or more of X-Rite’s affiliates.
  * To governing regulatory authorities or as may otherwise be necessary for X-Rite to comply with a legal obligation or demand.  
In the event X-Rite decides to reorganize or divest our business through sale, merger, or acquisition, X-Rite may share Personal Data about you with actual or prospective purchasers. We will require any actual or prospective purchasers to treat this Personal Data in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy.

##  Your Privacy Choices

You have the right to see and get a copy of the Personal Data about you that we maintain as well as to ask us to make corrections to inaccurate or incomplete Personal Data about you. You have the right to receive data that you have provided to us in a machine-readable format and to transmit that data to another controller. You may also request the erasure of your Personal Data or the restriction of its processing, or object to the processing of Personal Data about you. To seek access to Personal Data about you, to file a concern, complaint, or request for correction, or to opt out of particular programs, please contact our Privacy Leader by clicking on the “Contact Us” link on the X-Rite Site you are using, by using the X-Rite contact information on the X-Rite mobile application you are using, or by e-mailing us at privacy@xrite.com. You may also send a letter to the following address:

X-Rite  
Privacy Leader  
4300 44th Street SE  
Grand Rapids, MI 49512  
USA

Your local Data Protection Authority is responsible for making sure that applicable privacy laws are followed in your locality. For more information about your privacy rights, or if you are not able to resolve a problem directly with us and wish to make a complaint, please contact your local Data Protection Authority.

##  Security

X-Rite maintains controls to protect and secure Personal Data, but when you share Personal Data online there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party could gain access to your information.

## Accessing Our Sites Globally

By using this site, you understand that your Personal Data will be collected, stored, and processed in the United States and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations. X-Rite may transmit Personal Data about you to affiliates worldwide. These affiliates may in turn transmit Personal Data about you to other affiliates. Some affiliates may be in countries that do not ensure an adequate level of data protection. Nevertheless, all affiliates are required to treat Personal Data in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. To obtain additional information regarding the safeguards we have in place for cross-border transfers of Personal Data, please contact us using the information provided in the “Your Privacy Choices” section.

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy

Check this Privacy Policy regularly, as we may change or update portions of this Privacy Policy from time to time, subject to any applicable consent requirements. Any changes will be promptly posted to this page and accompanied by a new effective date at the top of this page.
